儿时
When I was a kid,
我常想我长大后
I used to think about the kind of man
会是什么样的人
I'd grow up to be.
我从未想到我的人生会变成这样
I never thought my life would turn out this way.
（墨西哥 克雷塔罗地区）
你就是克里斯·雷德菲尔德
So you're Chris Redfield.
活死人方面的专家
The expert on the living dead.
大英雄
The big hero.
你肯定杀过很多吧
Bet you killed a lot, huh?
所以 专家先生
So, Mr. Expert,
有什么对付他们的建议吗
any advice on dealing with them?
有
Yeah.
你有朋友吗
You got friends? Heh, heh.
当然有朋友
Sure. I got friends.
- 家人呢 - 有
- Family? - Yeah.
有妻子 父母
Got a wife. My folks.
还有个小妹妹
A little sister.
有公司在制造
There's corporations out there creating viruses
把人变成生化武器的病毒
turning people into bioweapons.
目标包括你我
People like you and me.
还有你朋友 你家人
Your friends. Family.
有朝一日 你将面临一个选择
There will come a day when you'll be faced with a decision.
杀掉他们
Kill them
或是被杀
or be killed.
听上去并不是很英雄的行为 对吧
Doesn't sound very heroic, does it?
抱歉
Sorry.
我们正在接近目标
We're approaching the target,
我们再全过一遍 确保不会出错
so let's go over everything one more time so there's no mistakes.
目标是格伦·阿里亚斯
The target is Glenn Arias.
他因贩卖武器被全球通缉
He's wanted internationally for weapons trafficking.
卖的可不是M16步枪和简易爆炸装置
And we're not talking about M16s and IEDs here.
而是尖端的玩意儿
We're talking cutting-edge shit.
他喜欢跟
He likes doing business
有重大冲突的地方做生意
anywhere there's a major conflict.
情报显示 阿里亚斯现有一种BOW
Intel says that Arias is now in possession of a BOW,
即 生化有机武器
a.k.a. bioorganic weapon.
所以BSAA（生化恐怖防御与评估联盟）会来
That's why the BSAA is here.
他们懂得如何对付那些东西
They know how to handle those things.
我们的一名卧底 卡西·怀特
One of our undercover agents, Cathy White,
数周前 和他儿子扎克一同失踪了
went missing weeks ago, along with her son, Zack.
今天我们有两个任务
We have two objectives today:
找到他们
Find them
并抓获格伦·阿里亚斯
and grab Glenn Arias.
通讯检查
Comm check.
馆外没有动静
No movement outside the compound.
分成三队
Split up into three teams.
我们进去
We're going in.
安全
Clear.
天呐
Jesus.
你还好吗
Are you okay?
快去
Go!
扎克
Zack?
没错
Yeah.
快跑
Go!
雷德菲尔德 回话
Redfield, come in.
有人吗 到底是什么情况
Anybody. What the hell's going on?
立即撤离 快去直升机那
Emergency evac. Get the chopper now.
离开这里
Get out of here!
阿里亚斯
Arias.
多亏了你 我不得不把生意转至别处
Thanks to you, I'll have to move my business somewhere else.
你个王八蛋
You son of a bitch.
拜托
Please.
我是个生意人
I'm a businessman.
我把好产品向任何有意购买的人提供
I make good products available to anyone who wants to buy.
且价格合理
And at reasonable prices.
比如 这个
For example, this…
精美范本
exquisite specimen.
凯茜
Cathy.
混蛋
Bastard.
在地球上的最后时刻
The last moments on Earth
是最美的 你不觉得吗
are the most beautiful, don't you think?
我的产品就好在
The wonderful thing about my products
他们知道盟友与敌人的
is that they know the difference between ally
区别
and enemy.
《生化危机：复仇》
- 恭喜 - 恭喜
- Congratulations! - Congratulations.
不
No!
这一切都是为了你 亲爱的
This is all for you, my dear.
我的萨拉
My Sara.
（四个月后 芝加哥）
就是这个吗
Is that it?
就是这个病毒让所有人发疯的吗
Is that the virus that's making everyone flip out?
没错
Yes.
情况越来越糟
It keeps getting worse and worse.
到处都有袭击发生
Attacks are happening all over the place.
你从哪弄到这个的
Where'd you get this?
我以前没见过这段影像
I haven't seen this footage before.
这个还没被公开
It hasn't been released yet.
他们不希望公众恐慌
They don't want the public to panic.
你在跟我开玩笑吗
Are you kidding me?
美国已有20次袭击了
There's been like 20 attacks in the U.S. already.
BSAA在努力加以控制 但…
The BSAA is working to keep it under control, but…
但在我们找到原因
But it'll just keep happening
阻止它之前 仍会持续发生 对吗
until we find the cause and stop it, right?
没错
Exactly.
这是故意而为的
This is being done intentionally.
如果我们能找到幕后黑手…
If we can just find out who's behind it…
焦糖玛奇朵
Caramel macchiato?
没忘巧克力片吧
Did you remember the chocolate chips?
顶部还有生奶油
And the whipped cream on top.
很好
Good boy.
这是甜点 不是咖啡 你知道的 对吗
That's dessert, not coffee. You know that, right?
你意思是
Your point?
没什么 钱伯斯教授
Nothing. Nothing at all, Professor Chambers.
死人复活 被用作生化武器
The dead coming back to life and being used as bioweapons.
这些疯子公司在这国家
These insane corporations have caused
造成了太多悲剧
far too much tragedy in this country.
你觉得都一样吗
You think this is more of the same, then?
我不知道
I don't know.
根据以前的情况
Based on what's happened before,
这次感觉不一样
this time it feels different.
可能有新的幕后黑手
Someone new could be behind it.
这是疫苗模拟吗
Is that the vaccine simulation?
这次的受感染者显现了
The infected are exhibiting
不同的特性
different traits this time around.
我在试图抑制人造病毒
I'm attempting to suppress the artificial virus
因为它似乎是感染的基础
because it seems to be the base of the infection.
我看到计算化学系统在运作
I saw the computational chemistry system running.
我们已在制造试验药物了吗
Are we making a test drug already?
当然
Of course.
多年来 我们的技术已有很大进展
Our technology's come so far over the years,
制造一个样品用不了多久
making a sample doesn't take that long.
对了
Oh, by the way,
新的一批受感染尸体被送来了
we got another delivery of infected bodies.
有很多 30具以上
A lot. More than 30.
谁在取样本
Who's getting the samples?
今天学生们都出去了
The students are all out today.
然后…
And…?
我是博士后 我不做那种事
Oh, no. I'm postdoc. I don't do that.
好吧 悉听尊便 钱伯斯教授
Fine. Anything you say, Professor Chambers.
我的英雄
My hero.
什么情况
What the…?
（100%匹配）
（原型疫苗已完成）
（已分割并转移至注射器）
（已存储于制冷设备中）
（计算化学系统）
亚伦
Aaron.
不
No.
为什么是现在
Why? Why now?
是这里
Here?
这像是谋划好的
It's like it was planned.
瑞贝卡
Rebecca.
- 克里斯 - 你还好吗
- Chris? - You all right?
好久不见
It's been a while.
你该穿件防护服 或起码戴个面罩
You should be wearing a clean-suit or at least a mask.
是啊…
Yeah, well…
你怎么样
How you doing?
目前挺好
I'm fine for now.
我怎么不被检疫
But shouldn't I be in quarantine?
听着…
Look…
病毒若真那么容易传染
if the virus really was that contagious,
我们早就都死了
we'd all be dead already.
另外 检疫要很久 我现在就需要你
Besides, quarantine takes too long, and I need you now.
所以别担心
So don't worry.
我们会让你冲个热水澡 然后一切都会好的
We'll get you to a hot shower, and everything will be okay.
你还是老样子
Same old Chris.
警方报告称 嫌犯
Police reports say the suspects
是武装恐怖份子
were armed terrorists.
到目前为止 死亡人数据称已超过…
So far, the number of dead is reported to be over…
芝加哥郊外小镇的大屠杀…
The mass killing in this town outside of Chicago is under…
今天 一家房车公园内的突发暴力事件致使数十人遇难
Sudden outbreak of violence at a caravan park claimed dozens of victims today.
安大略的特别任务部队宣称
Ontario's special task force has declared
已控制局势 同时 这可能是此事件的官方声明…
the situation under control. While that might be the official statement on the incident…
是我
It's me.
（逃生平面图）
你不像是在休息啊
That doesn't look like you're resting.
热水澡有奇效
A hot shower does wonders.
- 这是你从实验室拿来的数据吗 - 是的
- Is that the data you took from the lab? - Yes.
既然我们知道这试验药物能用作疫苗
Now that we know the test drug works as a vaccine,
我们就必须把它尽快送到其他实验室
we have to send this out to other labs ASAP.
让它大量生产得越早
The faster we get this mass-produced,
能救的生命就越多
the more lives we can save.
或许吧
Yeah, maybe.
你来这是有原因的吧
There's a reason you're here, isn't there?
你在追捕某人
You're after someone.
是的 他叫格伦·阿里亚斯
Yeah, a man named Glenn Arias.
他是谁
Who's that?
他接手了新保护伞和三联的运营
He took over Neo Umbrella and Tricell's operations.
现在他在把它们创造的武器
He's selling the weapons they created
卖给犯罪集团及交战国
to crime syndicates and countries at war.
他是个死亡贩子
He's a merchant of death
用雇佣军和BOW帮他做肮脏的事
using mercenaries and BOWs to do his dirty work.
现在…
And now…
死人再次崛起了
the dead are rising again.
你确定阿里亚斯是幕后黑手
And you're sure Arias is behind it?
确定 在我发现你的研究
Yes. After I found out that your research
是世界上最先进的之后…
was the most advanced in the world…
你就乘上直升机来找我了
You hopped on a chopper and came to see me.
没错
Yes.
在我看到你的实验室被毁得有多糟之后
And after I saw how trashed your lab was,
就觉得坏人也知道你的研究
it looks like the bad guys knew about your research too.
我向世卫组织报告了我们的初步结果
Oh… I reported our initial findings to the WHO.
然后他们把它发送给了
And then they sent it to facilities
世界各地专攻疫苗的机构
all over the world that specialize in vaccines.
其中任一机构都可能泄露出去
The leak could've come from any of those places.
没错
Exactly.
阿里亚斯想破坏你的研究
Arias wanted to disrupt your research.
现在他有了你的数据 就更危险了
And now that he's got your data, he's even more dangerous.
我比较了新病毒的DNA
I compared the new virus's DNA
和手头所有的生化武器资料
to all the bioweapons we have on file.
基因序列极其接近光明异教用的寄生武器
The sequence is extremely close to the parasitic weapons used by the Los Iluminados cult.
你认为阿里亚斯可能是他们的一员
You think Arias might be one of'em?
据我现有信息来看 我不确定
Based on information I have now, I'm not sure.
看来我们该去跟一位真正的专家谈谈
Looks like we should go talk to a real expert.
真正的专家
Real expert?
真不敢相信这种时候你还看得进书
I can't believe you can read a book at a time like this.
我想这是消磨时间的一种方法
I guess it's one way to pass the time.
有人曾说 知识就是力量
Well, someone once said, "Knowledge is power."
弗朗西斯·培根
Francis Bacon.
只需一颗子弹 就能打倒敌人
It only takes one bullet to bring your enemy down.
但有了知识 你就能击败所有邪恶
But with knowledge, you can defeat all evil.
嘿 他们说的是真的吗
Hey, is it true what they say?
你从特种队员变成了科学怪人
You switched from special ops to science geek?
天呐 BSAA全是有奇怪履历的人
Man, the BSAA's chock-full of people with weird resumes.
你一定一直都很聪明
Bet you were pretty brainy to start with.
那你为何转职
So why'd you switch?
说来话长
That's a story.
我曾是浣熊市特战救援队的医生
I used to be a medic in the S.T.A.R.S. Unit in Raccoon City.
我觉得 某种程度上
I guess, in a way,
我一直对医学科学感兴趣
I've always been interested in medical science.
后来有一天 我决定把它作为职责 来阻止人们滥用它
Then one day, I decided to make it my duty to stop people from abusing it.
心想 这些公司
I thought, " Here are these corporations,
被人渣管理 捕掠弱者
run by scum, preying on the weak."
就像人类身上的疾病
They're like a disease on humanity.
我想找到解药 就和克里斯一样
I want to find a cure, same as Chris.
不同在于 他用肌肉 我用大脑
The difference is, he uses his brawn while I use my brain.
所以大脑和肌肉一同合作拯救人类
So brains and brawns working together to save humanity.
你觉得你们有多大机会
What do you think your chances are?
- 你这是什么意思 达米安 - 没什么
- What's that supposed to mean, Damian? - Nothing.
只是 如果这疾病就没解药呢
It's just, like, uh, what if this disease don't got no cure?
我们追捕的那些混蛋 他们对待生死
The assholes we're after, they treat life and death
就像掷骰子
like they shooting craps.
一群垃圾
Bunch of dicks.
嘿 我刚发现DC和达米安
Hey, I just realized DC and Damian
这次没谈论绝命毒师
aren't talking about Breaking Bad for once.
- 嘿 别开这头 克里斯 - 这剧很超前
- Hey, don't go there, Chris. - That shit's ahead of its time.
是了不起的杰作
It's a goddamn masterpiece.
（科罗拉多 洛基山脉）
注意点 可别吓到当地人
Careful you don't scare the locals.
你的潜行技术太渣了
Your stealth's for shit.
喝那么多酒有点早 里昂
It's a little early to be that deep in the bottle, Leon.
看看谁来了
Well, look who it is.
BSAA的金童和厚望博士
The BSAA's golden boy and Dr. High Hopes.
你们到底有什么事
What the hell do you want?
我有个任务 我们需要你的帮助
I got a job. We need your help.
我在休假
I'm on vacation.
我们来谈谈光明教
Let's talk about Los Iluminados.
记得他们用的哪种BOW吗
Remember the type of BOWs they were using?
这是很久以前的事 我不记得了
That's so long ago, I don't remember.
然后呢 你就在这
So what, you just gonna sit around here
再坐一周 什么也不做
another week and do nothing?
我从不考虑那么长远
I never make plans that far ahead.
- 嘿 再来一瓶 - 别给他
- Hey. Another bottle here. - Cancel that.
- 嘿 你以为… - 够了 好吗
- Hey, who the hell do you…? - Enough! All right?
你想怎么样 雷德菲尔德
What do you want, Redfield?
你想怎么样 里昂
What do you want, Leon? Heh.
别喝了
Cut the shit.
伙计们 别这样
Guys, come on.
里昂 很抱歉
Leon, I'm sorry
打扰你休假
to interrupt your vacation,
但事情不严重我们也不会来
but we wouldn't be here if it wasn't serious.
我们觉得你可能有些情报 我们现在就需要
We think you might have some intel, and we need it now.
什么情报
What intel?
二号目标已确认
Second target confirmed.
留她活口
She stays alive.
干掉其他人
Finish the rest.
收到
Copy that.
听着 这玩意儿传播得又快又广
Look, this shit's spreading fast and thick.
我大学里的所有研究员和职工都被感染了
All of the researchers and staff at my university were infected.
又这种事
This again, huh?
我就像被困在一个该死的循环之中
It's like I'm stuck in a goddamn loop.
- 什么 - 你在说什么
- What? - What are you talking about?
知道在特区爆炸的那炸弹吗
You know that bomb that went off in DC?
当时我的任务就是阻止恐怖份子
Well, it was my mission to stop the terrorists.
我们到了汇合点
We got to our rendezvous point
某个混蛋出卖了我们
and some asshole ratted us out.
炸弹爆炸了 都市特警队的所有人
The bomb went off and everyone on Metro S.W.A.T.,
我的整支队伍 全死了
my whole unit, gone.
我一直不停地战斗
I keep fighting and fighting, and fighting.
可情况只是越来越糟
And instead of seeing an end to this shit,
看不到这一切的终结
it just keeps getting worse.
我的人生就该如此吗
Is this what my life's supposed to be?
对抗活死人和制造他们的混蛋
Fighting the living dead and the bastards that make'em?
这一切的意义是什么
What's the point of it all?
听着…
Look…
这是格伦·阿里亚斯 一个军火贩子
This is Glenn Arias, an arms dealer.
他在黑市的交易非常见不得人
His deals on the black market are so shady
这让他登上了政府的刺杀名单
they landed him on a certain government's hit list.
一颗制导炸弹在他婚礼上从天而降
A smart bomb was dropped on his wedding.
于是他失去了他的家人和妻子
He lost his family and his wife.
现在他满腔怨恨
And now he's got a grudge.
被袭之后 他隐匿了起来
After the attack, he went underground,
但现在他带着BOW回来清算旧账了
but now he's back with BOWs and a score to settle.
不可思议的是 他说他的产品
Here's the kicker, he said his products
能辨识目标
have targeting capabilities.
就我所见而言 我相信他
From what I've seen, I believe him.
所以一边是军火贩子
So you got an arms dealer on one side,
另一边
and on the other,
是在婚礼上投炸弹的政府
a government dropping bombs on weddings.
- 谁是坏蛋 - 阿里亚斯
- Who's the bad guy here? - Arias!
我们的任务就是拿下他
And it's our mission to bring his ass down!
- 是你的任务 不是我的 - 该死的 里昂
- Your mission, not mine! - Goddamn it, Leon!
别这样 里昂
Stop! Leon.
发生了这么多事
With everything that's going on,
你只是坐在这里 为自己感到遗憾
you just sit here and feel sorry for yourself.
而你 你在让怨恨支配你
And you? You're letting a grudge get the better of you.
天呐
God…
真不敢相信你俩竟如此相似
I cannot believe how alike you two are.
你在说什么
What are you talking about?
你们现在表现得就像两个自私的小鬼
You're acting like a couple of selfish brats right now.
病毒就在我们的鼻子之下
The virus is right under our noses.
一直如此
Always has been.
我没明白
I don't follow.
我们不用找阿里亚斯
We don't need to look for some new virus
感染人用的新病毒
that Arias is infecting people with.
病毒就蛰伏在每一个人的体内
The virus is lying dormant inside of everyone.
你也一样
Even you.
我们要找的是触发物
What we need to find is the trigger.
某个激活潜伏病毒的东西
Something activates the latent virus,
只有阿里亚斯知道是什么
and only Arias knows what it is.
但在我们找到之前
But until we find that out,
每个人 无论生死 都是他的潜在武器
everyone, living and dead, are his potential weapons.
如果我们不马上搞清楚
If we don't figure this out right now,
就不会再有这样的小镇
there won't be little towns like this
让你借酒消愁了
for you to drink your sorrows away in
永远不会再有
ever again.
我创造了一种疫苗
I created a vaccine,
在自己身上试了 它奏效了
and I tried it on myself and it works.
但在我们搞清阿里亚斯如何触发病毒之前
But until we find out how Arias triggers the virus,
谁又知道它是否对其他人同样有效
who knows if it'll work the same for everyone else.
我的血藏有答案
My blood holds the answers.
我死了就把它交给你们信任的实验室
If I die, get this to a lab you trust.
我无法想象你俩所经历的事
I can't imagine what you two have been through.
但我知道你俩没一个是那种
But I know that neither one of you are the type of person
会在世界毁灭之际还坐着争论的人
who would sit here and argue while the world dies.
你们不是那种人
That's not who you are.
还是说你们是
Or is it?
我那么说不是很好
That wasn't very nice of me.
里昂
Leon!
帕特里西奥
Patricio!
慢着 听我解释
Wait, wait! Let me explain. Unh!
- 里昂 - 这就是我说的那个人
- Leon! - That guy I told you about.
- 出卖我队伍的那个人 - 你不明白
- The one that sold out my unit. - You don't understand. Unh!
- 就是这家伙 - 请别这样
- This is the guy. - Please, stop.
- 嘿 你干嘛 - 公事 没事的
- Hey! What do you…? - Official business. It's okay.
- 里昂 别这样 - 你想干嘛
- Leon, come on! - What do you want?
别这样 你是我唯一认识的安全维和组织人员
Please. You're the only one I know from the DSO.
我的家人 你必须救救他们
It's my family. You've got to save them.
什么
What?
我的妻子和女儿都在西班牙
My wife and my daughter are in Spain.
光明教馀党在出钱
An arms dealer is getting paid
给一个军火贩子
by the surviving members of Los Iluminados
发动大规模的生化恐袭
to launch a large-scale bioterror attack.
我知道得太多 他们要杀了我和我的家人
I know too much. They're going to kill me and my family.
你听到他说的没 今天是我们的幸运日
Did you hear what he said? It's our lucky day.
幸运 你疯了吗
"Lucky"? Are you crazy?
- 他能带我们找到目标 - 你在说什么
- He's gonna lead us to our guy. - What are you talking about?
格伦·阿里亚斯 这名字耳熟吗
The name Glenn Arias ring a bell?
- 你怎么知道 - 我会读心术
- How do you know? - I'm psychic.
我需要你的帮助 我的家人
I need your help! My family!
我来帮你搞搞清楚
Let me get this straight.
你想害死我
You try and get me killed,
现在却要我救你家人
and now I'm supposed to save your family?
这样如何
Well, how about this?
你先告诉我们你知道的
You tell us what you know first,
然后我们再决定是否帮你
and then we'll decide if we help.
王八蛋
Son of a bitch!
他被跟踪了
He was followed!
我的家人
My family.
拜托了
Please.
救救她们
Save them.
该死
Damn it.
瑞贝卡
Rebecca!
一号目标已击杀 二号目标已活捉
Target one down. Target two secured.
DC 他们在旅店攻击了我们 还带走了瑞贝卡 追踪他们
DC, they hit us at the hotel and took Rebecca. Track'em.
我认得那大家伙 他是阿里亚斯的人
I know the big guy. He's with Arias.
阿里亚斯为什么想要瑞贝卡
What's Arias want with Rebecca?
不知道 我只想救她回来
I don't know. I just want to get her back.
我的假期毁了 是又毁了
There goes my vacation. Again.
嗨 亲爱的 是我
Hi, honey, it's me.
你能找到那个你说会帮忙的人吗
Were you able to get the man you said would help?
我很害怕
I'm so scared.
塞莱娜想爸爸了
Selena misses her daddy.
- 帕特里西奥 在吗 - 我能和爸爸说话吗
- Patricio? Hello? - Can I talk to Papa?
- 帕特里西奥 - 妈妈
- Patricio? - Mama.
- 你是谁 - 我能和爸爸说话吗 求你了
- Who is this? - Can I talk to Papa? Please.
帕特里西奥在哪 让我丈夫听电话…
Where's Patricio? Put my husband on the phone right…
他死前把这给你是有原因的
There's a reason he gave that to you before he died.
或许有我们需要的答案
It might have the answers we need in it.
我们有瑞贝卡的手提电脑
We have Rebecca's laptop.
我们有线索
We have leads.
听着 伙计
Look, man,
我需要你
I need you.
我成功地赋予了他们新的生命
I succeeded in reanimating them,
但我还没研究出
but I haven't figured out
如何防止身体腐烂
how to keep the bodies from rotting away… yet.
实践出真知
Practice makes perfect.
见见我的客人们
Meet my guests.
我的家人和我的一些挚友
My family and some of my dearest friends.
瑞贝卡·钱伯斯教授
Professor Rebecca Chambers.
欢迎
Welcome.
我是格伦·阿里亚斯
I'm Glenn Arias.
据说你找到了我商品的解药
I heard you found a cure for my merchandise.
年纪轻轻就聪慧过人啊
For someone so young, you're quite brilliant.
我找到的不只是解药
A cure isn't the only thing I found.
是吗
Really?
请说下去
Please, tell me more.
我搞明白潜伏病毒是如何被激活的了
I figured out how the latent virus is activated.
兽性病毒 教授 简称A病毒
Animality Virus, Professor. A-Virus, for short.
你的BOW能辨识攻击目标
Your BOWs can tell who they're supposed to attack.
这是个不错的武器卖点
That's a good selling point for a weapon.
改造出这种特性
Engineering them with that trait
一定让你大费周折
must have been difficult for you.
但我知道你是怎么做到的
But I know how you did it.
这种病毒有三株
There are three strains of the virus.
第一株感染他们
One infects them.
第二株作为触发物
A second acts as a trigger.
第三株能让你选择
The third gives you the option
你的目标是谁
of choosing who your target will be.
一种灭活病毒
A sort of inactivation virus.
就是疫苗
The vaccine.
再开次地图
Bring up the map again.
她一定认为这些疫情爆发事件有关联
She must have thought these outbreaks were related.
看到它们都集中在大湖区周围吗
See how they're all concentrated around the Great Lakes?
如果她说的是真的
If what she said is true,
这东西可以蛰伏在人体内
and this thing can lay dormant inside people,
天知道有多少人被感染了
God knows how many are infected.
你把基础病毒混进了饮用水中
You mixed the base virus in drinking water.
了不起
I'm impressed.
你怎么发现的
How did you figure it out?
我注意到疫情爆发
I noticed a huge concentration
大量集中在大湖区周围
of outbreaks around the Great Lakes.
那又正好是
Which just so happens to be
饮用水的主要来源
a major source of drinking water.
但那都不是你谋划的 而是偶发事件
But they weren't planned by you. They happened by accident.
在某些罕见的情况下
It seems under certain rare conditions,
潜伏病毒无需触发病毒就能被激活
the latent virus can activate without the trigger virus.
说到触发病毒
Speaking of, the trigger virus
很可能是用一种气体
is probably distributed through the air…
通过空气散播的
by a gas.
而这些病毒本身要么没有效力
By themselves, these viruses either have no potency,
要么有激活失败的风险
or they run the risk of activating on their own.
但一旦结合
But when combined,
就会成为高效可控的生化武器
they become an effective, controllable bioweapon.
太棒了 教授
Nicely done, Professor.
难怪你能在浣熊市幸存
It's no wonder you survived Raccoon City.
如果触发物是空气传播的 那就更难控制
If the trigger's airborne, it's harder to control
它的去向或感染目标
where it goes or who gets it.
所以阿里亚斯一定用了某种疫苗
So then Arias has to be using some type of vaccine.
他就是这样来控制疫情蔓延的
That's how he controls the spread of an outbreak.
他先对他不想感染的人注射疫苗
He vaccinates anyone he doesn't want infected first.
这样更有利于武器的精准性 看见没
Which makes for a more accurate weapon. See?
（潜伏病毒 触发病毒 疫苗）
你完成了对A病毒的研究功课
You've done your homework on the A-Virus.
那接下来呢
So now what's next?
研制试验解药对我并非难事
It wasn't hard for me to engineer a test cure.
而且现在我知道它有效
And now that I know it works,
我的团队有我的研究资料和我的血
my team has my research and my blood.
你所谓的商品
Your "merchandise, " as you put it,
很快就会被市场淘汰
will soon be obsolete on the marketplace.
我不想这么说 但你的研究并不完整
I hate to say this, but your research is incomplete.
真正的解药 在注射后 你是不会被袭击的
If you had found the cure, you wouldn't have been attacked after you took it.
但你还是被袭击了 对吗
But you were, weren't you?
不过无所谓了
Not that it matters.
你和你的疫苗将不久于世
No, you and your vaccine will soon be out of time.
明天 世界将会变得不同
Tomorrow, the world will be a different place.
阿里亚斯在谋划一起大事件
Arias is planning something big.
帕特里西奥知道太多了
Patricio knew way too much about it.
所以他才被杀
And that's why he was killed.
我知道发生了什么
I know what happened.
他们来杀你
They came to kill you,
可被杀的却是你爱的每一个人
but killed everyone you loved instead.
那天是你的婚礼
It was your wedding day.
对我来说 时间在那天停止了
The day time stopped for me.
那是萨拉
That's Sara,
我的妻子
my wife.
你看起来很像她
You look so much like her.
我们的相遇并非巧合
It's not a coincidence that we met.
而是天意
It's fate.
等等
Wait.
你这是想干什么
Where are you going with this?
我在重办婚礼
I'm redoing the wedding.
这次是和你
This time with you.
我会重写过去
I'll rewrite the past.
瑞贝卡
Rebecca,
来见下萨拉
meet Sara.
我们会很幸福
We're going to be so happy.
转念一想
On second thought…
我要把你的手臂换成萨拉的
I'm going to replace your arm with Sara's.
也许这会改变你对我的看法
Maybe that will change your mind about me.
他要对纽约使用触发病毒吗
He's gonna use the trigger virus on New York?
看上去是这样
That's what it looks like.
他疯了
He's out of his mind.
如果疫情爆发被认为无法控制
"If the outbreak is deemed uncontrollable,
标有绿A的罐子
"tanks labeled with a green A
内有疫苗 可随时使用
"contain the vaccine and are ready to deploy.
地点保密
Location classified."
我们要做的就是找到那东西
All we have to do is find that stuff,
然后就能让所有人恢复
and we can change everyone back.
就像按一个安全开关
Like flipping a safety switch.
如果你是阿里亚斯 你会把它放哪
But if you were Arias, where would you keep it?
能快速到达的安全处
Someplace he can get to fast. Someplace secure.
他在纽约的藏身处
His hideout in New York.
我们也肯定会在那找到瑞贝卡
And I bet we'll find Rebecca there too.
我们得快点散播
We need to expedite the release.
我们已安排在早高峰时段
We're set for morning rush hour.
我有预感 BSAA会来碍事
I have a feeling the BSAA will be heading our way,
所以我们需要对策
so we need that countermeasure.
你在谋划另一场袭击
You're planning another attack.
我在谋划我们的未来
I'm planning our future.
我们的时代就此开始
Our time starts now.
- 我们的 - 没错
- "Our"? - Yes.
我们将与我最后一位朋友
With the last of my remaining friends,
一起开始新的生活
we will begin our new life together.
是时候了
It's time.
爸爸
Dad…
祝我好运
Wish me luck.
天呐
Oh, my God.
亚历克斯 亚历克斯
Alex! Alex!
我叫救护车
I'll call the ambulance.
现在别打不通啊 该死的
Not now, goddamn it.
（纽约警局 安东尼·石冢）
大家都注射了一剂瑞贝卡的疫苗吧
Everybody get a dose of Rebecca's vaccine?
很好
Good.
增援部队的情况如何
What's the status on the reinforcements?
BSAA和纽约警局特警队正在地面激战
BSAA and N.Y.P.D. SWAT are on the ground in the thick of it.
州警还要三个小时才能到
The state police won't get there for another three hours.
这就表示 我们必须靠自己抓捕阿里亚斯了
So that means we have to nab Arias all by ourselves.
太棒了
Fantastic.
情况越来越糟了
Yo! The signal's getting worse.
他们在用油罐卡车喷射病毒
They're using tanker trucks to spray the virus.
他不是想转化一两千个人
He's not trying to turn a couple thousand.
他是想转化所有人
He's trying to turn them all.
我们得处理掉那些油罐
We need to take out those tankers.
钱伯斯教授的研究报告称
Professor Chambers' research says
这种病毒不耐受热
the virus can't handle heat.
它和汽油的燃点一样
It's got the same flash point as gasoline.
完美 我们来点根火柴 看它燃烧吧
Perfect. Let's light a match, watch it burn.
我希望我们能先去救瑞贝卡
I wish we could get to Rebecca first,
但那些油罐得优先处理
but the priority is those tankers.
所以我们有三件事要做
So we got three things to do.
一 炸掉油罐 二 救出瑞贝卡
One, blow up the tankers. Two, get Rebecca.
三 夺取疫苗 将其配发全市
Three, grab the vaccine and deploy it on the city.
- 还要抓住阿里亚斯 是四件事 - 你说了算 老大
- And grab Arias. Four things. - Whatever you say, boss.
DC 纳蒂亚 你们在鱼鹰上行动
DC, Nadia, you guys work from the Osprey.
收到 克里斯
Roger that, C.
来自BSAA的礼物
Gifts from the BSAA.
他们说他们目前只给我们弄这些了
They said that's the best they can do for us for now.
摩托车归我了
Dibs on the bike.
处理掉油罐 就去阿里亚斯那会合
Once the tankers are down, rendezvous at Arias' place.
我们可能要根据实际情况
Depending on the situation, we might have
先找到那疫苗 再去救瑞贝卡
to put Rebecca on hold until we find that vaccine.
了解
Got it.
准备好没
Well, you ready to rock?
你开玩笑吗
Are you kidding?
行动吧
Let's do this.
达米安 见鬼
Damian! Shit.
该死
Damn it.
有主意吗
Any ideas?
我来把狗引开
I'll lead the dogs away.
你去再炸些油罐 行吗
You go blow up some more tankers. Good?
好的
Yeah.
来啊 伙计 来啊
Here, boy. Come on!
这版触发病毒比上一版更好
This version of the trigger virus is better than the last.
更强 你的血是关键
Stronger. Your blood was the key.
非常感谢
Thank you so much.
不幸的是 增强毒性意味着
Unfortunately, increasing the toxicity means
它没法再通过气体下毒
it can't be administered via gas anymore.
所以 我恐怕得用注射这种老办法
So it's back to the old needle, I'm afraid.
我很抱歉
My apologies.
我们的模拟若正确
If our simulations were correct,
它就应该会在半小时后开始起效
it should start working in half an hour.
已炸掉三辆 寻找下一辆
Three down. Going for the next one.
很高兴再次见到你 雷德菲尔德先生
Nice to see you again, Mr. Redfield.
阿里亚斯
Arias.
多亏了钱伯斯教授
Thanks to Professor Chambers,
我们把病毒变得更强了
we made the virus much stronger.
如果你能再待20分钟
If you can stick around for, oh, another 20 minutes,
你就会见识到有多强
you'll see how strong.
我迫不及待地想要你见见被改进的全新瑞贝卡
I can't wait for you to meet the new and improved Rebecca.
问题是
The question is,
你对她下得了杀手吗
do you have it in you to kill her?
我的死人大军会把
My army of the dead will change
这世界变得更美好
the world for the better.
这将纠正近几年战争导致的不平衡
It will correct the imbalance caused by recent wars.
如果你能活得够久
If you stay alive long enough,
你就能和我看着我的BOW
you can watch with me as my BOWs
将那些最强大的国家
bring down the most powerful nations,
逐个击败
one by one.
你该进精神病院 混蛋
You belong in a nuthouse, asshole.
很遗憾 我没疯
Unfortunately, I'm not crazy.
我要复仇
I want revenge.
（打开）
我在按下重启世界的按钮
I'm hitting the reset button on the world.
我的商品 我的BOW
And my merchandise, my BOWs,
都很适合做这件事
are the right tool for the job.
- 里昂 - 抱歉 我来晚了
- Leon. - Sorry I'm late.
我不得不走楼梯
I had to take the stairs.
或许这就是我一直想要的
Maybe this is what I've always wanted.
一个在烈焰中的世界
A world in flames,
只剩下死人
where only the dead remain.
瑞贝卡的时间不多了
Rebecca's running out of time.
那我们分头行动
Then let's split up.
瑞贝卡
Rebecca.
你还好吗
You okay?
克里斯
Chris…
别 等下
No, no, no. Wait, wait.
疫苗在哪
Where's the vaccine?
告诉我
Tell me!
你就一定要救她
You just had to try to save her.
你太好揣测了 克里斯 这是你的弱点
You're so predictable, Chris. That's your weakness.
见鬼
Shit.
瑞贝卡
Rebecca.
你必须杀了我
You have to kill me.
不行
No.
我们会找到疫苗
We'll find the vaccine.
再坚持会儿就好
Just hang on a little longer.
迪亚哥
Diego,
最终阶段
the final stage.
释放吧
Unleash it.
雷德菲尔德
Redfield!
找到了
Found you.
我要把你断肠碎脏
I'm going to spill your guts all over.
纳蒂亚
Nadia!
迪亚哥
Diego!
见鬼
Shit.
接招
Catch.
再见 混蛋
Bye-bye, asshole.
瑞贝卡
Rebecca?
还有一件事要做
One more thing left to do.
那就做吧
So let's do it.
儿时
When I was a kid,
我从未想到我的人生会变成这样
I never thought my life would turn out this way.
又一次 我们发现自己心回初衷
And once again, we find ourselves back where we started.
什么意思
What do you mean?
我们打倒坏人
We got the bad guys.
希望自己让世界变得更安全一点
Hope we made the world a little safer.
嘿 克里斯
Hey, Chris.
怎么了
Yeah?
我们这样能持续多久
How much longer can we keep going on like this?
不知道
I don't know.
我从不考虑那么长远
I never make plans that far ahead.